# **MICHEAL SANDERSON**

Motivated and detail-orientated chief financial officer with over nine years of experience in the industry. Redesigned operational flows and assisted in the carrying out of seven acquisitions, which all contributed to increasing annual revenue by 78%. Proven leadership track record and able to work effectively in high-pressure environments.

789 Third Street, San Francisco, CA 12345 m. 5 a nd er so n@you remail.com {123} 456-7890

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **CHIEF FINANCIAL OFFICER**

ABC LLC, San Francisco, CA August 2015 - Present

- Develop budgets and strategic plans for day-to-day operations for a \$14 billion company
- Develop annual financial budgets, including rolling forecasts in coordination with the operations manager
- Ensure that the company complies with federal and state laws and regulations
- C lose ly wo rk with the C EO and to p exec utives regard in g a 11 maj or train section s such asacquisitions, joint ventures, partnerships, and mergers
- · Develop forecastingto analyze profitable business ventures

### **ASSISTANT FINANCIAL OFFICER**

LMB Technologies, San Francisco,CA June 2011 - August 2015

- Executed the core financial processes, including vendor set-up, administration of bank accounts, and account reconciliation
- Implemented a new accounting system that reduced input errors by 15%
- Raised sales by 120% by refocusing marketing and spending plans towards more profitable avenues
- Analyzed and presented the company's financial reports to senior management in a timely manner

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science in Accounting

The University of California, San Francisco, CA September 2005 - June2009

Master of Business Administration

The University of California, San Francisco, CA Septem be r 2009 - Ju ne 2011

### **KEY SKILLS**

- Financial analysis
- Communication
- Leadership
- Decision making
- Organization